Yalın Eren Deliorman

Software Developer

Test-driven, Responsible, and Task-Oriented professional with 4+ years of experience in IT and defence applications development. Proven success applying TDD and clean code principles to solve complex industry problems. Proficient in Back-end, frontend, modules integration, and agile development.

yalin.deliorman@gmail.com

Ankara, Turkey

github.com/ydeliorman

+905058293523

linkedin.com/in/valinerendeliorman

stackoverflow.com/users/12328682/yalin-eren-deliorman

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Nokia

11/2019 - Present

Ankara, Turkey

- Developed a web inventory tracking system for Turkey's one of the biggest ISPs which has more than 50 million users.
- Improved system performance and refactored the code. As a result, nearly 500 000 daily API requests are reduced to 10, making code more robust and dependency amongst modules is decreased.
- Increased the automation capabilities of the system and reduced 6 days of monthly job to 5 minutes.
- Implemented new modules using Test Driven Development (TDD). Wrote unit tests to older classes that have a critical part in the system.
- Contributed to customer meetings and obtained the requirements for new development requests or existing bugs.
- Fixed 1 billion of routers data that is kept in the database according to customer's requirements.

Software Developer

Ayesaş

04/2017 - 11/2019

Ankara, Turkey

- Contributed to the Turkish government's first helicopter project's and first distributed architected UAV mission planning software.
- Developed using Test Driven Development and reach at least 80% coverage on classes.
- Designed and wrote Software Design Document (SDD) and Software Requirements Specification (SRS) documents to fulfill customer's standards.
- Learned Luciad's front-end frameworks which are new to the whole team and gave a presentation to the development team about our possible way of implementation.
- Developed application's frontend via Luciad's Lightspeed, Lucy and Fusion frameworks. Refactored code according to the company's coding standard before official releases for customers.
- Developed microservices using GRpc which enables bi-directional streaming between user and application, while encrypting and gathering data in small packages.

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Sports Timer App (Flutter) ✓

Spring Boot, Data, Security, Docker Project ☑

FastAi - Deep Learning Projects 🗗

CERTIFICATES AND TRAININGS

Professional Scrum Master I (PSM I)

AWS Innovate Conferences Certificate of Attendance

Udemy Certificates for AWS, Flutter/Dart and Unity.

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Turkish

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

SOCIAL ACTIVITIES

EDUCATION

MBA

Hacettepe University

2018 - 2020

Ankara, Turkey

Computer Science Bilkent University

Bilkent University Voluntary Mentor for continuing students Bilkent University IEEE Member Voluntary Worker at LÖSEV

08/2012 - 01/2017 Ankara, Turkey